Rachel Dowdy

Whether I am working directly with your data, or building the front-end, I will take to it quickly and efficiently. I am a fast learner and work well in groups or alone. Since my education thus far has been on the topics of many things at once, I am capable of being a flexible asset to suit your needs. PLEASE VIEW MY WEBSITE:

https://radowtay.github.io/webpage-practice/index.html

9801 Boulder Hill Street, San Antonio, TX 78250 (210)415-5487 racheladowdy@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

Northside ISD, Folks Middle School — Orchestra Director

Iuly 2017 - November 2021

Many jobs, including inventory, accounting, data engineering, administrative duties, lesson planning, newsletter creation, department event calendar management, source private lesson teachers, event planning, mass communication in a 200+ student program

Basis.ed, BASIS San Antonio Medical Center — Orchestra/Choir Director

Iulv 2015 - 2017

Recruit and grow program; build library; event planning and logistics; lesson planning

Terra Nova Violins, San Antonio — Studio Administrator

May 2013 - July 2014

Manage studio schedule; recruit students and match with appropriate instrument teacher; mass communication; manage scheduling and appointments; clean and decorate studios; customer service

EDUCATION

Rice University via UTSA, Online Data Analytics Bootcamp — *Certificate soon!*

November 2021 - June 2022 (CURRENT)

Data Analytics Bootcamp: VBA, Excel macros, Python, Jupyter Notebook, GitHub, Matplotlib, pandas, Leaflet, JavaScript, HTML-5, Bootstrap, CSS, APIs, Flask

University of Texas at San Antonio — *Music, with focus in Education*

August 2008 - May 2013

PROGRAMS AND LANGUAGES

VBA, Excel macros, Python, Jupyter Notebook, GitHub, Matplotlib, pandas, Leaflet, JavaScript, HTML-5, Bootstrap, CSS, APIs, Flask, R, Tableau, SQL, PgAdmin, SQLite,

PROJECTS

Paranormal Traffic Webpage — SQL, Flask, html, css, Python, Javascript, API, Leaflet

Created a webpage that can access the sourced data, which has three interactive maps that show density of the three topics we chose. Group project.

https://github.com/JWatson1102/Project_3

Pymaceuticals Analysis — Jupyter Notebook, Python, Matplotlib

Created a JupyterNotebook detailing data concerning lab mice and subsequent tumor sizes in relation to medications administered using statistics and data visualizations.

https://github.com/radowtay/matplotlib-challenge

IMDB Movie Data — APIs, Jupyter Notebook, Python, Matplotlib

Created theories concerning dataset, then used analytical tools to develop a presentation showing data renderings of our findings. Group project.

https://github.com/radowtay/Project-1

Weather Findings Webpage — Jupyter Notebook, pandas, html, Bootstrap

Used images from a previous project and created a webpage to detail and layout the findings from that project. https://github.com/radowtay/Web-Design-Challenge